In the last lecture I talked about where to put your data transforming logic.
Son konumada, veri dnm mantnz nereye koyacanz hakknda konutum.
Now on the same page, if you chose the action creator, here's another utility method you might want to
imdi ayn sayfada, eylem yaratc yllarn ve her faydal yntemini setiyseniz, Funk'larla
know when working with thunk,
alrken bilmek isteyebilirsiniz.
so with asynchronous code handled by redux-thunk, for example our storeResult here. We return a function
Yani asenkron kod, redux phunk tarafndan ele alnr, rnein maaza saldrlar, redux phunk tarafndan
which gets dispatch handed into it as an argument by redux-thunk, which we can call to dispatch the action
argman olarak gnderilen bir ilevi geri getirir; bu ilem, async kodumuz
once our async code is done, actually redux-thunk can pass as an additional argument, getState,
bittikten sonra eylemi gndermek iin gerekte okunur x function pass as ek bir argman devlet edinir.
that is a method we can execute to get the current state.
Bu, mevcut durumu elde etmek iin uygulayabileceimiz bir yntemdir.
Sometimes in your asynchronous code, you need to be able to reach out to the state prior to your to-be-
ezamansz kodunuzda, eyleme gnderilmeden nce eyalete ulamak zorundasnzdr.
dispatched action,
Bazen
let's say you want to save some data for a given user and you have the id of the user stored in your
Belli bir kullanc iin baz verileri kaydetmek istediinizi ve Giudecca durumunuzda saklanan
redux state, you can then get it with getState,
kullancnn fikrini alp, get state'i elde edebileceinizi varsayalm.
for example here, we can get the old counter by executing getState here and simply accessing the counter
rnein, burada get state'i altrarak eski sayac elde edebiliriz ve sadece counter property get state'ye erimek, elbette
property, getState will give us the complete state which of course has a counter property or to be precise
bir Count zelliine sahip olan ya da redktrmzn durumu oluturmas nedeniyle kesin olmas
since our reducers make up the state and we have two of them,
iin tam durumu verir ve iki tane onlardan.
we can get the counter just as in the counter container in mapStateToProps, we have to access ctr.counter.
Tezgah tpk harita durumundaki saya konteynrnda olduu gibi alabiliriz, bu yzden
So we can do that
biz bunu ehirimize ulamalyz.
here, .ctr.counter in the action creator, thanks to the second argument passed into it by redux
Senin nokta CPR bizim kpek sayac eylem yaratcs ikinci argman sayesinde Redux phunk
thunk.
tarafndan geirildi.
Now this old counter can then be output here,
Artk bu eski saya burada kt olabilir.
old counter and I saw I have a typo there,
Eski saya ve orada yazm hatas olduunu grdm.
let's fix that.
Onu dzeltelim.
So now if I save this and I store my result,
imdi bunu kurtardm ve sonularm saklyorum.
I actually get my old counter printed here on the right in the console, the blue 10 here.
Aslnda eski numaram alyorum ya da konsoldaki mavi 10'un sanda olduunuzu yazdracam.
That's the old counter I get right before dispatching this event which then actually leads to the code
redktrde yrtlen ifre zmeye yol aan olay gndermeden nce aldm eski saya.
executed in the reducer.
Bu, daha sonra gerekten
Now this is kind of related to what I said in the last lecture,
imdi bu, son derste sylediimle bir tr ilgilidir.
if you need it, it's a nice utility function,
htiyacnz olursa, gzel bir yardmc program ilevi.
don't overuse it though.
Buna ramen fazla kullanmayn.
I try to write my action creators and reducers in a way that I don't have to use getState, instead
Eylem yaratclarm ve yapmclarm, bunun yerine devlet edinmek zorunda kalmamak iin yazmaya altm.
you can pass all the data you need in your async action creator like the user id into it by accepting
htiya duyduunuz tm verileri, async eylem oluturan kiiye, kullanc kimlii gibi, argman olarak kabul
it as an argument.
ederek ona geirebilirsiniz.
That of course means that you need to have access to the data you need in your action creator in the
eylem yaratcsna ynlendirilen eylemi gerekten gnderdiiniz kapsle erimeniz gerektii anlamna gelir.
container where you actually dispatch the action leading to the action creator.
Bu tabii ki, ihtiyacnz olan verilere, eylem yaratcsna ve
So here storeResult which leads to the async action creator,
Yani burada hikaye, async action yaratcs oluyor.
here we would then have to pass this user ID or whatever it is and for that,
Burada, bu kullanc kimliinden gemek zorundayz ya da ne olursa olsun biz ldk.
we of course need to have access to that user id in our container.
Elbette konteynrdaki o kullanc kimliine eriebilmeliyiz.
But that is something we might be able to expect and we should build our app accordingly.
Ancak bu bekleyemeyebileceimiz bir ey ve buna gre uygulamanz gelitirmeliyiz.
If you just can't do that or don't want to, you have getState as a fallback and you can use it,
Bunu yapamazsanz ya da istemiyorsanz, devleti bir geri dn olarak alrsnz ve eklentiyi kullanabilirsiniz.
just don't over use it.
Sadece fazla kullanmayn.
Don't put too much logic in there, at least is the route I take in my bigger react applications.
Orada daha fazla mantk koymayn, en azndan yeniden hareket uygulamamdaki rota en azndan.